▍2026 辛辛那提 ATP1000 第三轮
霍达尔 6-2 6-1 塔比洛 · 赛后场上采访
Rafa, congratulations once again, a
拉法 再次恭喜你
really tight match against Shapovalov,
上一场对沙波瓦洛夫很胶着
today a match where you won more
今天这场你赢得更轻松
comfortably, what improved in your game
具体是哪里进步了？
specifically today?
说说看
Well, I think that match against Denis
对丹尼斯那一场
gave me a lot of confidence, you know, I
给了我很多信心
push, you know, to the limit, you know,
我把自己逼到了极限
and I worked very hard to win that
为赢下那场拼得很凶
match, but yeah, everyone, every match
但每一场都难打
is tough, you know, so not because the
不能因为比分
result, you know, seems a bit more
看着轻松一些
easier, that means that the match is
就说这场球好打
easier, you know, I think everyone plays
这里每个人都打得很好
here very good, so I had to be my best
所以今天要赢塔比洛
today to beat Tabilo and I had to be my
我必须拿出最佳状态
best level, you know, and in all the
最好的水平
matches here.
这里每一场都一样
Tabilo beat you in Indian Wells, it was
印第安维尔斯他赢过你
a closer match in Washington which you
华盛顿那场更接近
won today, more clearly in your favor,
今天你赢得更干脆
how much do you and your dad spend time
你和你父亲会花多少时间
analyzing opponents to work out a clear
研究对手 定出清晰的战术？
strategy? Well, it's difficult, you
这很难说
know, because I'm new in the tour, you
我刚上巡回赛时间不长
know, so all the players that I'm
我遇到的球员
playing, most of them are new for me,
大多是新面孔
but I mean, the players that I've
但交过手的那些
already played against, it's easier, you
准备起来会容易些
know, to prepare a match, I could say,
大概知道会遇到什么
because you can kind of have an idea
因为你心里有个数
what you're gonna expect, but every
但每场球都不一样
match is different, every tournament has
每站赛事条件也不同
different conditions, so you just have
所以你只能
to be very focused, you know, on doing
保持高度专注
the things right, and I think most
把该做的事情做好
importantly to focus on yourself, you
我觉得最重要的一点
know, not focusing on the opponent,
是专注在自己身上
which is also important, but I think
对手当然也要研究
more important in you.
但更重要的是你自己
Just lastly, you're so good at being
最后一个问题
humble and staying in the moment,
你一直很谦逊 很沉稳
remarkably so, is there a little boy
你心里有没有一个小男孩
inside you jumping up and down that
在跳起来
you're winning all these matches?
为这些胜利？
Well, I'm happy obviously to get this
拿到这样的胜利
type of wins, you know, and to be able
我当然开心
to play in these big stages, you know,
能打上这样的大舞台
and center court of the Masters 1000 is
站上大师赛的中央球场
something that I dreamed about when I
那是我小时候的梦想
was a kid and when I used to watch all
那时候我在电视上
the matches on TV, so yeah, super
看所有的比赛
grateful, you know, that in what
所以真的很感激
position, you know, I am now to be able
现在能有这样的位置
to play, but as always, and I've always
去打这些比赛
said to be the same kid, you know, as I
但我一直说
was when I used to watch the matches on
要做同一个孩子
the TV. Congratulations once again.
就是当年电视机前那个我
Thank you.
再次恭喜 谢谢